Guide to the Fox Chapel Garden Club Records, 1931-2010 AIS.2011.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Fox Chapel Garden Club Records
1931-2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Fox Chapel Garden Club (Fox Chapel, Pa.)
AIS.2011.10
17.25 Linear Feet (12 boxes, 18 scrapbooks)
This collection documents the functions and activities undertaken by the Fox Chapel Garden Club (FCGC). The material, dated 1931-2015, includes organizational records such as board and membership meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, yearbooks, publications, special project files, correspondence, awards, and club ephemera.
History
The Fox Chapel Garden Club (FCGC) was founded June 6, 1931 at the home of Mrs. A. P. Hill, with 26 founding members, for the purpose of having regular meetings to discuss gardening. By 1941, the club had grown to 60 members. In 1933, under the direction of Mrs. Harold Nomer and Mrs. A. P. (Ella) Meyer, and with the support of the Pittsburgh City Council and other neighborhood garden clubs, the FCGC rented a building in Schenley Park for the purpose of disseminating gardening information to the community. In 1935, this institution was formally opened as the first Pittsburgh Civic Garden Center and served 90 local garden clubs.
Over the course of the organization's history, its members have been involved in civic and environmental advocacy, particularly in the areas of conservation and "garden therapy" outreach. In 1948, Mr. Richard Boyles, the first municipal manager of the Borough of Fox Chapel, whose wife Ruth was the Borough's tax assessor and a member of the club, purchased acreage along Squaw Run Road to protect the Trillium plants that grow in the area. The "Trillium Trail" has been maintained by the FCGC since 1949, which uses it as a teaching resource for the local community schools about wildflower cultivation, forestry, and environmental conservation.
Beginning in 1950, the FCGC began a "garden therapy" program at Leech Farm Hospital and the Veterans' Affairs Hospital on Delafield Road to help rehabilitate patients. In 1975, the FCGC opened a garden therapy program at Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital (later renamed HealthSouth), which lasted for 32 years. In 1996, the club established an outdoor garden at Harmarville for therapists and patients to use.
The club has maintained long-standing memberships with the Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania (originally as a member of District VII, and later incorporated into District IX) and the National Council of State Garden Clubs, Inc. The club has also organized several events and programs for the Pittsburgh community at large over the years, including flower shows, an annual "Garden Market" sale (also called "May Market"), and holiday auctions. The club has been regionally recognized for its outreach and service, and has been the recipient of multiple awards. It has also received consistent local press coverage, and its two club members, Ruth Boyles and Ruth Scott, have been extensively profiled in the news and by the club.
Related Material
Ezra C. Stiles Collection, 1916-1953, AIS.2000.08, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Garden Club of Allegheny County Records, 1913-2010, AIS.2006.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
The Fox Chapel Garden Club (FCGC) Records contain a number of record types including: official minutes, reports, club yearbooks, publications, photographs, special project files, correspondence, awards, scrapbooks, and ephemera. FCGC is a member of District IX of the Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania (GCFP), as well as the National Council of State Garden Clubs, Inc., and these affiliations are documented within the collection.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Fox Chapel Garden Club on November 6, 2011.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following 13 series:
Series I. Meeting Notebooks, 1931-1949
Series II. Meeting Minutes, 1951-2013
Series III. Executive Board Minutes, 1950-2013
Series IV. Financial/Treasurer's Reports, 1953-2015
Series V. Yearbooks, 1932-2011
Series VI. Project Files, 1933-2010
Series VII. Publications, 1934-2014
Series VIII. Correspondence, 1954-2011
Series IX. Affiliations & Awards, 1949-2015
Series X. Scrapbooks, 1958-1996
Series XI. Maps, 1934-1993
Series XII. AV Materials, 1950-2009
Series XIII. Artifacts
Previous Citation
Fox Chapel Garden Club Records, AIS.2011.10, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Video recordings (physical artifacts); Audiocassettes; Photographs; Maps; Scrapbooks; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Fox Chapel -- Societies, etc.; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County -- Societies, etc.; Environmental quality -- Pennsylvania -- Fox Chapel; Environmental quality -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Associations; Fox Chapel (Pa.); Environment; Gardening -- Therapeutic use -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Environmental protection -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Minutes (Administrative records); Financial records; Correspondence; Stiles, Ezra C.; Fox Chapel Garden Club (Fox Chapel, Pa.); Boyles, Ruth; Scott, Ruth
- Meeting Notebooks, 1931-1949; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains the earliest records of the club, beginning with the minutes from their first meeting on June 6, 1931. The series includes minutes, executive board minutes, and treasurer's reports from 1931-1949, recorded in bound ledgers, journals, and on loose notebook pages.
  - Organizational Meeting, June 6, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - June 1931-November 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - November 1932-November 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - November 1933-November 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - January 1935-November 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - December 1935-August 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - September 1937-November 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - By-Laws, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - November 1939-October 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - October 1944-November 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - January 1946-November 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting Minutes, 1951-2013; II.
  This series contains a record of the club's general meetings, submitted by the recording secretary, for the years 1951-1959 and 1975-2013. The records include annual reports and committee reports. The series also contains correspondence, programs, and flyers that were kept with the minutes in their original binders. Club newslettters were removed and refoldered (See Box 6, Folders 6-8). There are no minutes for the years 1957 and 1960-1974.
  - 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1975-2004 (Box 1, Folder 15-27)
  - 2006 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1998-2009 (Box 10, Folder 1-9)
  - 2011-2013 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1950-2013; III.
  This series contain a record of the Club's Executive Board meetings from 1950-1959 and 1975-2013. There are no minutes for the years 1957 and 1960-1974.
  - 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1955-1956; 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1975-1996 (Box 1, Folder 31-37)
  - 1997-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - 1998-2005 (Box 10, Folder 12-17)
  - 2007-2009 (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
  - 2011-2013 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1953-2015; IV.
  This series contains the monthly and annual reports of the Club's treasurer from 1953-2015. The series also contains revenue and expense reports from special events (May Market, flower shows), as well as the annual report of the club's donations to various charities. There are no records for the years 1957, 1960-1966, and 1968-1974.
  - 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1975-2009 (Box 2, Folder 7-17)
  - 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1998-2005 (Box 10, Folder 22-27)
  - 2007-2015 (Box 10, Folder 28-31)
- Yearbooks, 1932-2011; V.
  This series contains the annual yearbook produced by the club for every year from 1932-2011, with the exception of only 1981 and 1989. Each yearbook contains the constitution and by-laws of the club, which is amended every 20 years. The yearbooks also contain a listing of the executive officers, a listing of past presidents and honorary members, that year's meeting schedule and details, committee names and members, and a directory of all members of the club.
  - 1932-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19-55)
  - 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 56-60)
  - 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 60-64)
  - 1998-2011 (Box 3, Folder 1-13)
- Project Files, 1933-2010; VI.
  This series contains all of the records of the club's projects, activities, interests, and events they were directly or indirectly involved with from 1933-2010. The records are divided by subseries into the categories of activities the club was active in, including gardening, environmental conservation and education, garden therapy, and fundraising. There is significant correlation between the subjects in these files and the subjects of the photographs in Series XII.
  - Conservation Activities, 1960-2007; 1.
    This subseries contains all records of the club's environmental education and conservation activities. The subseries contains both general environmental awareness topics as well as specific topics of interest to the club (see Gypsy Moth, Deer Overpopulation, Squaw Run Area Watershed Association). Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Conservation Committee, 1982-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Deer Overpopulation, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Environmental Education Curriculum, 1967-1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gypsy Moth, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Insects/Pests, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Invasive/Non-Native Plants, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Lyme Disease, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Recycling Projects, 1989, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Squaw Run Area Watershed Association (Borough Flooding), 1976-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Resources, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mary's Garden, 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Shoe Recycling Project, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Flower Shows, 1933-2010; 2.
    This subseries contains all records of the club's flower show activities from 1933-2010. The subseries is primarily composed of files from the manuals of the club's largest shows, Pittsburgh in Bloom (1991) and Pittsburgh on the Move (1999). However, the subseries also contains additional flower show manuals and programs from Fox Chapel Garden Club, the National Council of State Garden Clubs, Inc., and other regional garden clubs.
    - Fox Chapel Garden Club, Flower Show Programs, 1933-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Fox Chapel Garden Club, Flower Show Programs, 1981-2009 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Flower Show Programs, Other Clubs, 1975-1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Flower Show Programs, Other Clubs, 1999-2006 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - National Council of State Garden Clubs guide: "Educational Exhibits Explained", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - National Council for State Garden Clubs handbook for flower shows, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Guestbook for "Pittsburgh in Bloom" & "Pittsburgh on the Move", 1991 & 1999 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Pittsburgh in Bloom" show manual, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
    - "Pittsburgh on the Move" show manual, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 33-35)
    - "Pittsburgh on the Move" miscellaneous files, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "It's Blooming Ellington" flower show, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Various flower show materials, 1970-2004 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Show Materials, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Gardening Activities, 1975-2010; 3.
    The subseries contain all records of the club's gardening interests, activities, and community fundraisers, particularly the annual May Market held by the club.
    - Gardening Resources, 1989-2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Garden Market / May Market, 1978-2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - May Market- Garden Center Files, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - May Market- Orders, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - May Market- General Information, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - May Market- Treasurer's Files, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - May Market- Report, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - May Market- Expenditures, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - May Market- Miscellaneous, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Garden Therapy, 1959-1996; 4.
    This series contains all records of the club's involvement with Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital, from the establishment of the Garden Therapy program in 1959 through the fundraising and construction of the Outdoor Therapy Garden at the HealthSouth (formerly Harmarville) between 1994-1996.
    - Garden Therapy, Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital, July 1, 1959 - June 30, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Garden Therapy, Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital, 1982-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Garden Therapy Fundraiser, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Additional Garden Club Projects, 1949-2014; 5.
    This subseries contains the records retained by the club for special events and projects. The folders are arranged alphabetically.
    - 75th Anniversary Party, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Garden Club Auctions, 1999-2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Recipes in Bloom" cookbook design files, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Trillium Trail, 1949-1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Scholarship Donation (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Glitter and Glow, 2008-2014 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
- Publications, 1934-2014; VII.
  This series contains publications either created or collected by the Fox Chapel Garden club members over the course of their history. It is divided by subject into three categories: Fox Chapel Garden Club, Fox Chapel Borough, and general materials. The club materials include anniversary books, newsletters, the club's two cookbooks, newspaper clippings, and a report by Ezra C. Stiles (see AIS.2000.08) comissioned by the club. The Borough materials include the Borough master plan, reports, and short history books. General materials include publications on conservation, flower arrangement, and gardening. Publications of the Garden Club Federation and Pennsylvania and the National Council of State Garden Clubs are included.
  - Fox Chapel Garden Club, 1934-2014; 1.
    This subseries contains publications created by and/or regarding the Fox Chapel Garden Club. The records are arranged alphabetically and include club publications, newsletters, cookbooks, and newspaper clippings retained by the club. This subseries also includes a landscaping report by Ezra C. Stiles commissioned by the club.
    - Anniversary Publications, 1981-2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - By-laws, 1953-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "Things We Grow in Our Kitchens" cookbook (online), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Recipes in Bloom" cookbook (2 c.), 2009 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ezra C. Stiles Report- "Fox Chapel Roads & Roadsides", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Garden Gab" newsletter, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Through the Garden Gate" newsletter, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Through the Garden Gate" newsletter, 1996-2010 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930-2011; 1980-2007 (Box 5, Folder 9-13)
    - 70th Year Anniversary History (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Club Website, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "Garden Gab" newsletter, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 36-37)
    - "Through the Garden Gate" newsletter, 1993-2014 (Box 10, Folder 38-41)
    - Yearbook Material, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Fox Chapel Borough, 1956-1994; 2.
    This subseries contains publications produced by or about the Borough of Fox Chapel.
    - Borough Master Plan, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Fox Chapel- The Story of a District" book (2 c.), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Fox Chapel History" (c. 1), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "Fox Chapel History" (c. 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Reports on Fox Chapel Borough, 1988-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - General Materials, 1926-2010; 3.
    This subseries contains general publications retained from the club. They are arranged alphabetically, and the subject topics include gardening, flower arrangement, and environmental conservation.
    - "Bicentennial Trees of Allegheny County, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Conservation publications/newsletters, 1966-2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Japanese Flower Arrangment for Modern Homes", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Flower arrangment manuals/clippings, 1949-1958 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvannia publications/newsletters, 1981-1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania publications/newsletters, 1974-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Keystone Gardner, 2001-2010 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Gardening newsletters/bulletins, 1968-1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Gardening Publications, 1926 & 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Home Garden Journal, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5-8)
    - "House Plants for the Purple Thumb", 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "A Garden Potpourri", 1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Officers and Committees, 1989-2000 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Clubs and Conservation Publicity, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Clubs and Conservation Publicity, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Clubs and Conservation Publicity, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Clubs and Conservation Publicity, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Keystone Gardener, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Keystone Gardener, 2003-2007 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - National Gardener, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - National Gardener, 2002-2004 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1954-2011; VIII.
  This series contains letters and printed emails sent and received by the club from 1954-2011. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically, and is grouped by type of communication, meaning either external (business) or internal communication. Additionally, there are two folders of letters and emails of correspondence between the club and the Garden Federation of Pennsylvania and Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital. The Harmarville correspondence primarily documents the club's decision to discontinue Garden Therapy at the hospital in 2006.
  - Business Correspondence, 1970-2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Internal Correspondence, 1977-2011 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - GCFP Correspondence, 1954-2007 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital, 1990-2006 (Box 6, Folder 14a)
  - Postcards / Thank You Cards (Box 6, Folder 14b)
  - Internal and External Correspondence, 1998-2005 (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
  - GCFP District IX Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 58)
- Affiliations & Awards, 1949-2015; IX.
  This series contains all records of the club's affiliations to local, state, regional and national garden club organizations. It also contains awards and awards applications to the club's affiliate organizations for the club and its members' efforts and programs.
  - Affiliations, 1924-2009; 1
    This series contains all records of the club's affiliations to the Garden Club Federation of Pennsylvania (GCFP), the National Council of State Garden Clubs, Inc. (NCSGC) and the Central Atlantic Region of the NCSGC (CAR). In addition, files on the club's two most notable members, Ruth Dye Boyles and Ruth Jury Scott, and files collected on Mr. Ezra C. Stiles.
    - GCFP General Files/ Board of Directors, 1990-2002 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - GCFP District VII, 1994-2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - GCFP District IX, 2000-2011 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - NCSGC Inc., 1992-2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Ruth Dye Boyles, c. 1971-1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Ruth Jury Scott, c. 1976-1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Ezra C. Stiles, c. 1924-1935 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Audubon Society, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - CAR, 2001-2003 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - District VIII, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - District IX Board, 2002-2006 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - District IX Board, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - District IX, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - District IX, 2002-2006 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - District IX, 2002-2006 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - District IX, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - NCSGC, 2002-2005 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - NCSGC Directory, 2007-2009 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Ruth Scott Memorial Material (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Western Pennsylvania Conservancy, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Awards, 1949-2015
    This series contains award applications submitted by the club, as well as awards received from GCFP, NCSGC, Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital, and other groups. This series also contains nomination files for the club's Honorary members (the most senior level of membership). Some awards were for individual members or the club and its actions as a whole.
    - GCFP Awards & Applications, 1949-1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - GCFP Awards & Applications, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - GCFP Awards & Applications, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - GCFP Awards & Applications, 2001-2010 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - NCSGC Awards & Applications, 1950-1991 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - NCSGC Awards & Applications, 1995-2004 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Various Gardening/Garden Therapy Awards, 1974-2000 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Honorary Memberships, 1955-2001 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Awards Programs (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - GCFP Flower Show Awards (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - GCFP Publication Award, 1987-2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - GCFP Honor Roll, 1997-2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - GCFP Yearbook Award, 2000-2006 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - GCFP Video Program Award, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - GCFP Publication Award, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - GCFP Specialized Publication Award, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - GCFP Seed Money Award, 2007-2015 (Box 11, Folder 18a-18b)
    - GCFP Awards Manual, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - GCFP Penny Pines Project Award, 2013 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - GCFP Yearbook Award, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - NCSGC Awards, 2003-2009 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - NCSGC Plantings for Special Places, 2013 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - NCSGC Certificate for Long-Term Members, 2014 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - District Laurels, 1973-2012 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - District Daffodil Award, 1987-2012 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - District VII Honor Roll for Exceptional Achievement, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - District VII Blue Rosette Award, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - District IX Award of Honor, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - District IX Yearbook Award, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - FCGC Certificate of Appreciation, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - FCGC Honorary Members, 2005-2007 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - FCGC Community Award, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Award of Honor, 2001-2006 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Award of Honor: Marguerite Hannon, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Certificates of Appreciation, 2006-2013 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Cheveron Conservation Award, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Civic Achievement Award, 1987-2012 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Conservation Award, 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Gold Seal Award, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Governor's Trophy Award, 1999-2001 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Harmarville Garden Therapy Awards, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Holiday Auction Award, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Honor Roll of Exceptional Horticulturalists, 1964-2006 (Box 11, Folder 44-45)
    - Horticulture Excellence Award, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Hunt Trophy Award and Applications, 1973-1999 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Keystone Gardener Literacy Award, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Donation to Scholarship Fund, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Pennsylvania Horticultural Society Awards, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Publicity Pressbook Award, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Rally our Region Award Application sample, 2014-2015 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Regional Perennial Award, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Youth Activities Awards, 2006-2007 (Box 11, Folder 54)
- Scrapbooks, 1958-1996; X.